# Matthew Zuckman

I'm a passionate design leader—transforming patterns, insights, and opportunities into compelling experiences. I shift design cultures and build empowered teams. I develop product and marketing experiences that work across platforms, screens, and customer needs. And I've got the track record to prove it.

# **Employment History**

#### Yahoo

# Design Director, Communications

Mail, Calendar, Groups, Contacts, Notepad 2013-present

#### Yahoo

# Design Director, Commerce

Autos, Travel, Shopping, Homes, Games 2010–2013

# Publicis Modem VP/Director, User Experience

PayPal, LG, UBS, SunPower Foundation 2008–2010

# Real Branding Director, User Experience

Disney, ABC, ESPN, Anheuser-Busch, Lipton, Red Lobster, USGA 2007–2008

- Led the large scale front-end redesign of Mail and Calendar for an audience of 300 million customers
- Transformed the team's culture, tools, and the working models, increasing performance for the existing team while expanding the size and reach
- Strengthened the cross-discipline team via models that inspired deep thinking, ideation, efficiency, and strategic alignment
- Worked across the network to define hiring practices, charters, and reviews criteria to ensure the quality of talent and processes
- Led the development of lead-generation opportunities by focusing on meaningful values, increasing page views and time spent 30-50% across the portfolio
- Built a multi-disciplinary team of eight teammates within four months; expanded portfolio to take on additional business lines
- Directed the multi screen migration to the global publishing system; refining scope to preserve experience and revenue
- Drove the re-imagining of Autos, Travel, and Shopping by producing forward-looking visions that informed the strategy
- Oversaw the re-launches of PayPal's consumer and business sites, bringing double-digit growth in lead generation and adoption
- Supported LG Mobile's digital strategy by delivering rich-presence marketing experiences for all new phone releases
- Recruited and managed team of designers; directed utilization and billable percentages across teams and accounts
- Provided bench strength across the Publicis network by collaborating on projects and strategic initiatives in other offices
- Led the joint SOAPnet/agency team through all phases of large redesign project: developing community, architecture, and content strategies for all screens
- Grew the experience design practice by providing thought leadership, mentoring designers, and pitching new business
- Worked with company leadership to develop processes and deliverables, defining the scoping models for client engagements

# Earlier positions

#### **AKQA**

Microsoft Xbox, Target, Nike, Autodesk, McDonald's, 2008, 2010

# Masters Program Study Advisor, Academy of Art University

2008-2010

#### Senior User Experience Designer, McCann Worldgroup

Clorox, NBC Universal, 2007

## Senior User Experience Designer, Eleven Inc.

The Doctors Company, 2006-2007

#### Senior Information Architect, Tribal DDB

Clorox, Armor All, Hidden Valley, Fresh Step, NBC Universal, 2005-2006

#### Senior User Experience Designer, EVB

AT&T, Wrigley, Adidas, Leapfrog, 2005-2007

# Lead Interaction Designer, Enterpulse

Albertsons, 2004

# Information Architect, Grey Global Group

Oracle, Wells Fargo, 2003-2004

## Executive Producer, Epylon Corporation

1999-2001

# Producer, Foote, Cone & Belding

3Com, Sega Dreamcast, 1998 - 1999

## Producer, Think New Ideas

Silicon Graphics, 1997 - 1998

#### Designer, Printz Electronic Design

Silicon Graphics, 1995 - 1996

#### Education

# Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, RI

BFA, industrial design, with emphasis on human/machine interface design

# University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Liberal arts, with emphasis on economic and political sciences